<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tech on The Cafe</title>
    <link>https://binarydigit.cafe/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tech on The Cafe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;script src=&#34;https://status.lol/binarydigit.js?time&amp;link&amp;no-emoji&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://binarydigit.cafe/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Giscus for Comments</title>
      <link>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/giscus-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/giscus-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to remove webmentions from this website, in favor of trying out &lt;a href=&#34;https://giscus.app/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Giscus&lt;/a&gt;, a commenting system powered by GitHub discussions. Since most of the people I&amp;rsquo;ve run into on the nerdiverse(fediverse) who might read this website probably use Github, why not try to use a free comment system based on it. It also includes reactions which are cool to see for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve removed tinylitics since I tend not to ever glance at the data, just the kudos (which would be replaced by the Giscus reactions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll see how I like it for a while since it&amp;rsquo;s free and looks pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next step would be for me to add a &amp;ldquo;reply on Mastodon&amp;rdquo; button, in case folks don&amp;rsquo;t have a GitHub profile to comment and want to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/giscus-comments/feature-giscus.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitea for the Cafe</title>
      <link>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/gitea-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/gitea-cafe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw the news that the co-founder of Github was banned via &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39267200&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/defunkt/status/1754610843361362360&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    tweet here&lt;/a&gt;. Looks like it was taken care of pretty quickly, and is just a reminder than anyone using a third party service, no matter who you are, can get removed at any time, even if by mistake!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had my original Instagram account banned with no warning and no explanation. Extremely frustrating. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it back and support was abismal. I was sad about, but also was already on my way off that platform by deleting my images. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t rely on that account for Twitch or keeping in touch with many folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;m able to spend a little bit more a month on services, I decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pikapods.com/apps&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    PikaPods&lt;/a&gt; and spin up a Gitea instance. It was very easy, hardly any configuration needed, I was able to set up custom domain name, and it was cheap. The minimum specs that were enough for me to run a server is about $1.90 a month. I decided on this method rather then manually pushing to Codeberg since they don&amp;rsquo;t offer repo mirroring due to performance issues. I didn&amp;rsquo;t look up if Gitlab or Sourcehut do mirroring but this is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /notes/gitea-cafe/gitea-ss_huac058b461bbc987802bb3949b66b473c_243080_330x0_resize_box_3.png 330w,
        /notes/gitea-cafe/gitea-ss_huac058b461bbc987802bb3949b66b473c_243080_660x0_resize_box_3.png 660w,
        /notes/gitea-cafe/gitea-ss_huac058b461bbc987802bb3949b66b473c_243080_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w,
        /notes/gitea-cafe/gitea-ss_huac058b461bbc987802bb3949b66b473c_243080_1320x0_resize_box_3.png 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/gitea-cafe/gitea-ss_huac058b461bbc987802bb3949b66b473c_243080_660x0_resize_box_3.png&#34;
        alt=&#34;Gitea&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Gitea in the Cafe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have the energy and patience I might make a small Gitea or Forgejo instance on my Raspberry Pi since it&amp;rsquo;s for backup, but this is perfect for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/gitea-cafe/feature-gitea.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Old Tech Shows</title>
      <link>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/the-joy-of-old-tech-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/the-joy-of-old-tech-shows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love waking up in the mornings, making a cup of coffee, and seeing what Twitch streams are online. Today I noticed the thumbnail of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/oldtimeycomputershow&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    OldTimeyComputerShow&lt;/a&gt; channel and it featured Leo Laporte, to my joy, along with Patrick Norton, on TechTV. I absolutely loved when we had this channel at home (I was fortunate to grow up in a cable TV house) and it brings me back to my adult youth. This episode was aired in 2001 and was talking about computer firewalls and privacy online. How the times haven&amp;rsquo;t changed much 😂 I wonder if these episodes are available on the internet archive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/search?query=techtv&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    THEY ARE!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did find some Revision 3 content so I&amp;rsquo;ll check out if they have TechTV, my ultimate favorite nerd show. And yes I do follow everyone in their different endeavors who came out of TechTV current day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to lose all my time on the archive downloading episodes :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/the-joy-of-old-tech-shows/feature-techtv.png" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
