<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cafe on The Cafe</title>
    <link>https://binarydigit.cafe/tags/cafe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cafe on The Cafe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;script src=&#34;https://status.lol/binarydigit.js?time&amp;link&amp;no-emoji&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://binarydigit.cafe/tags/cafe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Not a Blogger</title>
      <link>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/notablog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/notablog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know what dawned on me today? After many years of short form &amp;ldquo;blogs&amp;rdquo;, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be a blogger. I miss tumblr style/short form content. I don&amp;rsquo;t sit down and write long stories or articles. I&amp;rsquo;ve changed a bit and I think it&amp;rsquo;s why I struggle with fomo and going back and forth to social media and back to my own platforms trying to blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love working on my website, making pages, and aesthetics. For example I signed back up for Tumblr and am so happy browing and reblogging. On Instagram, I usually consume but don&amp;rsquo;t really post, unless it&amp;rsquo;s for streaming or music content. On Mastodon I usually consume, boost, and sometimes post short things. It&amp;rsquo;s just funny how you realize you change after a while. And I don&amp;rsquo;t always need a blog, but when I want to write something I can do it here as a note, which is the whole point of a digital garden, and send it out to socials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a reminder to myself that I can do whatever I want here. That&amp;rsquo;s the whole point of the indieweb and to have fun again online. 💖&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:100%;position:relative;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/UvQVAw0B3G6QndwGxn&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34; style=&#34;position:absolute&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/notablog/feature-notes.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Website Setup</title>
      <link>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/hugo-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/hugo-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Static Site Generators 
    &lt;div id=&#34;static-site-generators&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#static-site-generators&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ages I resisted static site generators. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wrap my head around the complexity of them, or why I would need one. But then, I got to know the indie web, aka, the small web. The movement of people going back to focus on their own websites, owning a domain name, and publishing content on your website then out to other services, aka &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/POSSE&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    POSSE&lt;/a&gt; - Publish (on your) Own Site, Syndicate Elsewhere. I always wanted to keep that motto all these years, but kept jumping around from a social blog to another social blog, to Wordpress, and back.  Now I&amp;rsquo;ve landed on micro.blog, but even want to avoid using that in the future if I can help it. It helps save a few bucks a month as well as learn the intricacies of static site generators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Tinkering 
    &lt;div id=&#34;tinkering&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#tinkering&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since micro.blog is built with Hugo, I went back to trying to learn it. I first edited my micro.blog theme with the custom editor, and then decided to give Hugo a try on my own. Lo and behold, it finally &amp;ldquo;clicked&amp;rdquo;. I tried a couple of themes, and then landed upton this one, named &lt;a href=&#34;https://blowfish.page/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Blowfish&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;so awesome&lt;/em&gt;! It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly customizable and helped me learn so many details about Hugo. I then was able to push my git repo to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Netlify&lt;/a&gt; and have it hosted there for free! I&amp;rsquo;m super happy that I&amp;rsquo;m able to finally have a digital garden (cafe) and blog on my own domain, not worried about a major service going down, an acquisition, or paying a ton of money for hosting each month. I hope I can keep it running for a while and never go back to hosting again (unless they offer something that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist). Next up, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to import old posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/hugo-setup/feature-dino.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my Digital Cafe</title>
      <link>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my attempt at a new site with Hugo, finally, on my own domain and hosted via netlify/github! I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to do many things here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add webmentions, since ideally that would be the way folks respond or comment to my self hosted blog. I really like the fediverse and the small web, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve installed this correctly. If not I&amp;rsquo;ll keep trying :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added back the CS.SJoy.lol webring, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to set up the Indieweb web ring (first I need to finish some auth specs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love how to figure out how to import existing blog posts from my micro.blog, so eventually I can keep everything here. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this is possible, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a huge deal anyway if I can get everything set up properly. I can restart a blog at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy your stay, feel free to subscribe via RSS or say &lt;a href=&#34;https://binarydigit.cafe/about&#34;  &gt;
    hello&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://binarydigit.cafe/notes/hello/feature-rainbow.jpg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
